Last week was probably the craziest week
we've seen in AI so far this year. It
was so big that most of the AI world is
still talking about last week's news
this week. However, GPT5 and Google's
Genie 3 aren't the only interesting
things worth talking about. In fact,
there were quite a few other interesting
tools and stories that kind of flew
under the radar this week. So, I'm not
going to waste your time. Let's dive
right into the AI news that's worth
talking about this week. Starting with
the things you can actually use right
now, Microsoft rolled out a fun new
project called Copilot 3D, which allows
you to turn any image into a 3D model.
Now, this isn't a text to 3D or text to
image model. You give it an image and it
converts that image into a 3D object.
This is cool cuz you can use it for
things like creating 3D assets for game
development, miniature modeling, and
even 3D printing, web design. turn
graphics into 3D graphics for your site
and even for virtual reality. You can
pull these objects into virtual worlds.
This is currently freely available to
use for anybody. You can find it at this
URL here, but I will make sure it's
linked up in the description so you have
easy access. Once you're on this page,
you can click try now. You do have to
have a free Microsoft account to use it.
So, sign in with your Microsoft account.
And once you're logged into your
Microsoft Copilot account, if you're not
immediately redirected to the Copilot
3D, open up this sidebar menu here,
click into Labs, and you'll see Co-Pilot
3D right here along with some other cool
little toys you can play with inside of
Copilot Labs. But let's try the Copilot
3D here. And this doesn't work from a
text prompt. You have to give it an
image to start. So I want to try two
things. I want to generate an image and
pull it in. And I also want to see if it
works with like a realworld image that I
take. Can I take a photo of something,
have it generate a 3D version of the
real life object, and then be able to
import it into a game or something. So,
let's start by generating an image. For
this, I'm going to go ahead and use
Leonardo, which is my favorite image
generation, but full disclosure, I'm
also an adviser for them. And we're
going to generate an image of hard shell
taco roller skates, cuz why not? And
here's the image we'll be working with.
I'll go ahead and download this. We'll
jump back into Copilot 3D here. Upload
our image. And we'll select our hard
shell taco roller skate here. See how it
does. And honestly, not bad. It actually
only took maybe 20 seconds or so.
Really, really quick to generate. That
was what was most surprising to me was
how fast it actually did this. It sort
of made the shadows part of the object
here. But that's something that if you
know Blender, you could probably get in
and fix real quick. But I'm actually
really impressed with our 3D taco roller
skate here. So, one other thing I want
to test is I want to take a picture of
an object in the real world. So, maybe
I'll go take a picture of my guitars
real quick. All right, give me one
second. Take a picture of this guitar
right here. Let's see if we can figure
that out. So, here's the photo I'm
working with. It's actually missing a
string. One of my strings broke and I
haven't replaced it yet. But, I don't
think the 3D uh generator will notice
that. So, let's toss this image in and
see if it can actually generate based on
a real image. I don't see why it
wouldn't. I'll go ahead and close out of
this one. We'll upload a new image. This
time, we'll pull in the image I just
took. And let's um let's create that. I
don't know what it's going to think of
the background. There's actually like a
little outlet that's kind of being hid
by the guitar a little bit. Once again,
it was super fast. Let's see. I mean,
yeah, not bad. The head up here is like
really kind of wonky looking, but it's
it's not bad at all. It definitely lacks
some detail, but it's a great start. I
mean, I could probably clean this up a
little bit in Blender and 3D print it if
I wanted to or, you know, hang it on a
wall in a game in Unreal Engine and it
looks like a pretty solid guitar. I
mean, considering the fact that you
upload an image and it only takes like
15 seconds maybe to turn it into 3D,
it's really impressive, especially since
these models that were doing image to 3D
like a year ago, you'd have to wait like
a half a day. You'd submit it and it
would process in a cloud somewhere and
you'd come back like hours later to see
if it would finish. And now it's doing
it in like 15 seconds. And it obviously
knows what a guitar looks like. It's
probably in the training data cuz it
sort of figured out what the back would
look like. And that's that's got to be
based on existing data within the, you
know, in the training set. But pretty
dang impressive. And it's free to use.
Totally free over on Copilot Labs. So,
something fun to play with and check
out. If you're looking for another way
to generate highquality videos that
actually have sound, well, you can
actually do it through Perplexity. Now,
V3 is pretty expensive if you use it
directly through Google, but now there's
so many other platforms that use it, and
I believe Perplexity is using V3. I'm
not 100% sure, like, I can't confirm
that exactly, but I'm pretty sure it's
V3. But Perplexity now has video
generation on web, iOS, and Android. If
you're a pro subscriber, you get five
videos a month. If you're a max
subscriber, you can generate 15 with
even better quality. Real simple. If we
head over to perplexity.ai here, I am on
a pro plan, not the max plan, so I get
five generations a month. I've already
tested this once, so I've already used
one of my generations. But if I just
give it the prompt, just straight up in
perplexity, generate a video of a cowboy
riding a kangaroo on top of an erupting
volcano. And tell it to generate. You'll
notice we don't need to switch to any
special mode or anything like that. It
will just start generating. And it
totally changed my prompt, too. You can
see it has like a prompt optimizer where
it took my basic prompt and rewrote it
as a much stronger prompt. And now it's
trying to generate. I'd say it took
roughly a minute, maybe slightly less
than a minute. And here's what we got.
Let's go full screen with it. I got no
complaints with that. It followed the
prompt. I don't know what was roaring. I
don't think kangaroos really growl, but
it definitely did the trick. Now, I
don't know if this works with images.
Only one way to find out. Let's go ahead
and click on plus. Here I have this
image that my producer Dave made of a
Mountain Dew River with Dorito Mountains
and pizza buildings. Let's see if it'll
animate this. So, I will attach an
image. We'll attach the image that we
just were looking at. And let's see if
it'll create a video from the image.
Let's give it the prompt create a video
of a Mountain Dew River, Dorito
Mountains, and pizza houses using the
attached image. Let's see if it actually
generates off of that image. I think it
might have created a new image cuz we
can see here illustrating a creative
scene with mountains, a river, houses
inspired by the provided image. So, it
seems like it's creating a brand new
prompt inspired by the image and not
actually using the image we uploaded.
I'm wrong. It actually did use that
image. Here's what it looks like.
Complete with steaming pizza in a
flowing Mountain Dew River. So, yeah,
with Perplexity, you can go text to
video or image to video and it will
generate it with sound. It's 8 seconds,
which I think is kind of a hint that it
is using V3, but another platform to get
V3. And if you're already paying for
perplexity, it's a nice little bonus.
While we're on the topic of AI video,
the company Open Art, which was formed
by some previous Googlers, can now
create brain rot videos in just one
click.
I made them extra for you.
If you're not familiar with brain rot,
here's some quick examples.
You a shark, not more like blah blah
blah. Wiggle your fins, but can't drop
heat. You flop so hard even seaweed
beat.
Or maybe some of this.
Oh wow.
[Music]
Yeah, that's basically AI generated
brain rot, aka AI slop. Well, Open Art
just released a new feature called
one-click story. It allows users to
input a single sentence, a script, or
even a song and turn it into a one
minute video with a story arc. You know,
this whole like AI slop, brain rot sort
of stuff that's going around is not my
favorite use case of AI. In fact, I'm
sort of worried about the world getting
flooded with this stuff, but I'm going
to test it cuz that's what I do. I test
tools. And so, if I head over to
openart.ai, over on the left, they've
got this story section. If I click in
here, we've got options for character
vlog, music video, explainer video, or
from scratch. So, let's do a character
vlog and see. Pick your star. We've got
a few characters we can choose from or
we can go custom where we can upload a
reference image. For this example, let's
just use one of theirs. I'll use this
like penguin stuffed animal thing. Allow
outfit changes. Sure, why not? Vlog
topic. Let's go. Nina goes skydiving.
Let's make it 916. We'll let it auto
select the background music. And then we
can pick image models and video models.
Interesting. Okay. So, for our image
model, let's go ahead and leave it on
the character model. Best video model,
let's go cling 2.1.
Okay, so it's saying this is about a,000
credits. They only give me 500 credits
to start. So, maybe I have to go back to
Cling 2.1 standard. So, the amount of
credits they give you for free does not
cover the cost to generate one of these
videos. You can't even really test it.
That's unfortunate. Looks like you need
to be on their $14 a month plan to be
able to generate these one-click
stories. Kind of a bummer. They don't
let you at least do one for free. Okay,
so I bit the bullet and subscribed real
quick just cuz I want to see what this
looks like. Now I've got my 4,000
credits. Let's go ahead and create our
story. All right, and here's what it
generated for us.
We did it. We did it. We did it. Yay.
Now we see.
We did it.
We crawled through doggy doors with our
little pup. We did it. We did it. We did
it. Hooray. Okay, some things I love.
The airplane just kind of takes off
vertically here. Our penguin skydiving
and the parachute just changes to a
completely different parachute randomly
halfway down. But the thing about these
like sort of brain rot videos is that
the expectations aren't high. It's
almost like the jankiness is what sells
it. I guess just a bummer that you have
to actually pay to even generate one of
them. I consume a lot of AI and tech
content. So, if you asked me to remember
every YouTube video I watched, article I
read, or podcast I listened to from the
past week, I'd probably panic. Recall is
like having an AI powered memory. It
helps you save, summarize, and connect
everything you read, watch, or listen to
so you can go back to it later. Here's
how I use it. While I'm online, I use
Recall's browser extension to summarize
articles, YouTube videos, even 2-hour
long podcasts. I just click one button
and it gives me a smart summary I can
edit and save. And the best part is that
it automatically tags, organizes, and
connects all of the content inside this
knowledge base. Recall just rolled out a
new feature where you can chat across
everything you've ever saved. So instead
of digging through all of my YouTube
scripts, I can just ask Recall, "Go
through all of the AI tools I've already
tested in my videos, and give me a new
image generation tool I haven't tried
yet." Awesome. Can't wait to try this.
Plus, I can import thousands of past
notes, documents, bookmarks, even Tik
Toks. And Recall makes it all
searchable, connected, and ready to chat
about. You can try it for yourself at
getrecall.ai
and get 30% off with the code
Mattwolf30. The offer is valid through
October 1st, 2025. So, definitely jump
on it. Now, let's get back to the rest
of the video. We got an update out of
Notebook LM this week. We learned last
week, or maybe even a couple weeks ago,
that they were rolling out video
overviews. Well, now everybody has
access to video overviews, according to
Josh Woodward here. If you're not
familiar with Notebook LM, it's this
tool where you can throw in a bunch of
sources. They can be articles or
websites or YouTube videos or things
like that, and it will actually let you
chat with those documents, create mind
maps from those documents, create an
audio podcast with two hosts speaking to
each other, generate reports from those
documents like FAQs, study guides, etc.
And the newest feature is now a video
overview. So, it will actually generate
an explainer video based on all of the
content that you've loaded in. A few
weeks ago, I did a little fun test where
I had it make some content for me, a
little podcast around the birds aren't
real movement, which is like this
satirical conspiracy theory. Let's see
if it can create a decent video overview
on this topic. So, let's click video
overview. And uh I have no idea how long
this is going to take, but let's find
out. Okay, so it took about 10 minutes
to process this. Let's see what we got.
7 minutes and 27 seconds. The explainer,
birds aren't real. Have you ever, you
know, looked up at a pigeon and had a
weird thought like, "Is that a
government drone?" It sounds totally
nuts, I know, but it's actually the main
idea behind a movement that has
absolutely taken over the internet.
So, we've got a similar voice over to
what you get with the Notebook LM like
podcast voice, but now we actually have
a video over it. And we can see as I
sort of scrub through the video that it
makes a pretty decent looking like
slideshow style video. It looks really
nice, honestly. And the whole thing has
a voice over podcast over the top. It's
got a nice looking timeline.
Everything's pretty impressive. Now,
this isn't actually using V3, Google's
video model. I believe this is using
Google Vids, which is their AI model
that generates like slideshow looking
presentations. But pretty impressive
that we can give it some information on
any topic we want. it will go and create
like an audio podcast and then create an
actual slide presentation that looks
really really good to go along with that
podcast audio. I wouldn't be surprised
if pretty soon we're seeing like full-on
YouTube channels just crank out content
like this. Plug in a bunch of
information into Notebook LM, let it
spit out a video, hit publish. You're
probably going to start seeing that
quite a bit honestly cuz it really
doesn't look bad. Since we're talking
about Google, they rolled out a few new
updates this week over on the Google
website, including a new AI powered
Google Finance. So, you can research
your finance questions with AI. You have
advanced charting tools and real-time
data and news. So, if we head on over to
google.com/finance,
I don't believe the AI version of the
site is fully rolled out yet. If we look
at the article here, it does say over
the coming weeks in the US, you'll begin
to see the new experience with the
option to toggle between the new and
classic design. And I'm not seeing those
options, but supposedly you can ask
detailed questions about the financial
world and get a comprehensive AI
response. I was hoping I'd be able to
demo it for you, but it doesn't appear
to be rolled out on my end yet. Google's
also rolling out an AI update to its
flight deals. Rolling out this week in
the US, Canada, and India, the flight
deals tool surfaces relevant, affordable
flight options from multiple airlines
and booking sites. So, if we head to
google.com/travel/flights/dealss
and then let's click on go to Google
flights, I don't feel like this is the
AI experience yet either. So, supposedly
you'll be able to describe travel ideas
in natural language and flight deals
will surface affordable flight options
to match your ideas. This article here
does say the search feature will be
rolled out in beta over the next week
across the US, Canada, and India. So, as
of this recording, it doesn't appear to
be rolled out yet either, but those are
two new features that should be in
Google possibly by the time you're
seeing this video. Another feature we
got out of Google this week is inside of
Gemini, they've rolled out actually a
couple new features. One of them being
temporary chats. This is sort of like an
incognito mode for your chats. any chats
that you have in temporary chat, it
won't save them to your history. But it
also now understands your chat history.
So, anything that doesn't use the
temporary chat, you should actually be
able to recall in your current
conversations. Today, we're introducing
a new setting that allows Gemini to
learn from your past conversations over
time. When the setting is on, Gemini
remembers key details and preferences
you've shared, leading to more natural
and relevant conversations. This is
something we've had in chat GPT for a
while that I found to be very, very
helpful and beneficial, but now we're
getting it in Gemini. But not only are
we getting it in Gemini, Enthropic
rolled out that same feature this week
as well. Enthropic's cla chatbot can now
remember your past conversations, but
it'll only do so if you ask it to. So,
this one doesn't just automatically use
it for context with every new chat. You
have to specifically tell it to look at
your old chats. So, let's try this out
real quick. I usually use the Gemini
models over inside of AI Studio, which I
don't think has this feature yet, but I
do have some past chats in here that it
can pull from. So, let's go ahead and
see how it works.
A few moments later.
And well, it appears that this feature
isn't rolled out yet either. Knowing
what you know about me, what advice
would you give me right now? I wanted to
see if it would actually pull up past
history, and it says, "I don't have any
personal memories or access to our past
conversations." So, not rolled out yet.
When I look at Google's article here,
once again, we're rolling out this
feature over the coming weeks, starting
today, and apparently it hasn't rolled
out. This seems to be a pretty common
theme with a lot of the Google stuff.
Here's a cool feature that you're going
to have, but you don't have it yet.
Here's another cool feature you're going
to have soon. We promise, but not yet.
Here's a feature that you're going to
really, really like when we eventually
give it to you, right? The last three
things I tested, except for Notebook LM,
that one's working now. But let's go
ahead and try it with Claude. I do
believe Claude actually has rolled this
out. They didn't just announce that
they're going to roll it out and then
not actually roll it out yet. They
actually said it's a feature that you
can have and here have it. In fact, when
I go to claude.ai, I get this little
modal here that says, "Claude never
loses the thread. Now Claude can
reference past chats for relevant
context." So, we know that this is
working. And uh let's see. It says, "Hi,
Claude. What were some highlights from
our recent conversations?" It
automatically plugged in this prompt for
me just so I can test it. And we can see
it is pulling in past chats. And yeah,
it actually did a pretty good job. We
worked on a browser Bellatro clone. I
did that in a previous video. Library
Survivors game. We did that in a
previous video. No equipment daily
fitness app. Yep, that was another one
we did in a different video. Some other
things I've had some conversations
about. So, it is pulling in past
conversations. One thing I do like to
ask chat GPT and now we can ask Claude
and eventually ask Gemini was the one
you saw me just attempt to ask Gemini,
which is knowing what you know about me,
what advice would you give me right now?
And because it said you do have to tell
it to use previous chats, let's just go
ahead and remind it to use previous
chats. So I'll just update this prompt
to knowing what you know about me from
previous chats. What advice would you
give me right now? and it actually gave
some really personal, really tailored
feedback to conversations I've had. So
yeah, it's working perfectly in Claude
now. So if you like that feature in chat
GPT, but maybe prefer the style of
conversation you get out of Claude, this
update might be for you. So check that
out. And that was the last thing that I
had available to actually demo, even
though about three of the demos I wanted
to show off cuz I thought we had access
to them haven't fully rolled out yet.
But this was the last demo that I knew
we can show. But there's more news this
week, including some fun drama.
In my opinion, there is no greater
reality show than watching billionaires
duke it out and fight on social media.
And that's some of the drama we got this
week. Elon Musk this week went and
called out Apple saying Apple is
behaving in a manner that makes it
impossible for any AI company besides
OpenAI to reach number one in the app
store which is an unequivocal antirust
violation. Say I will take immediate
legal action claiming obviously that
OpenAI is more visible in the app store.
Sam Alman then retweeted Elon and said,
"This is a remarkable claim given what I
have heard alleged that Elon does to
manipulate X to benefit himself and his
own companies and harm his competitors
and people he doesn't like." Elon
clapped back on that same post. "You got
3 million views on your post, you liar.
far more than I've received on many of
mine despite me having 50 times your
follower count. Said Sam Alman, will you
sign an affidavit that you have never
directed changes to the X algorithm in a
way that has hurt your competitors or
helped your own companies? I will
apologize if so. And then even Grock,
somebody asked Grock, based on verified
evidence, Sam Alman is right. So just,
you know, a fun beef to watch play out
in public. Why these guys decide to do
this in public, I don't know, but I'm
enjoying following along. In other Elon
related drama, one of the co-founders of
XAI is actually leaving X. Igor
Babushkin, one of the co-founders of
XAI, announced his departure from the
company on Wednesday. He led the
engineering teams and helped build the
startup into one of Silicon Valley's
leading AI model developers. Now, it
doesn't seem like him leaving is over
any sort of drama or there's any bad
blood here cuz Elon even replied to his
tweet saying, "Thanks for helping build
XAI. We wouldn't be here without you."
And it looks like he's moving into like
venture capital. He's founding Babushkin
Ventures. But just interesting timing of
it all. Chat GPT5 comes out. Elon and
Sam Alman start beefing. And then all in
the same week, one of the co-founders of
XAI leaves. Just a lot of drama to pay
attention to. And finally, in the last
bit of drama this week, remember how a
few weeks ago we were talking about how
Meta was poaching a whole bunch of
people from all over the place, grabbing
people from OpenAI and from Google and
and they basically acquired Scale and
they're building this super intelligence
team. Well, now Microsoft is doing the
same thing to Meta. Microsoft is trying
to poach Meta AI talent and offering
multi-million dollar pay packages. And
the funny thing is Meta and Microsoft
actually work pretty closely together.
But yeah, Microsoft is out there trying
to offer like eight and nine figure
deals for talent at Meta, trying to get
them to come over to Microsoft. Again,
Silicon Valley billionaires fighting it
out is like the most fun drama for me. I
don't watch much reality TV. This is my
reality TV. All right. Now, there was
quite a few other things that happened
this week that kind of flew under the
radar, and I want to make sure you're
fully looped in. So, let's jump into a
rapid fire section.
Pew.
Let's start with the latest large
language models that came out this week.
We've got a few of them. Google released
Gemma 3 270 million M. So, it's a 270
million parameter model. We're used to
seeing a B here. It's not a 270 billion.
It's 270 million this time. So, this is
a small model that's designed to be
efficient and fast and even fit on small
phones. This isn't designed to be like a
GPT5 or Claude 4.1 mega model
competitor. It's meant to be fast and
efficient and run locally on whatever
device you're using. Mistral AI released
a new model this week. They released
Mistral Medium 3.1. You can use it over
on their Lech website and seems to be
fairly marginal improvements. You can
take a peek at their little chart here
of benchmarks and it appears to be just
a better model than their sort of
previous generation of models. Some of
the Quinn models from Alibaba got some
updates this week. QuinnB Quinn 3B A3B
257 and Quinn 3235B
A22B 257.
Okay,
both got ultra long context windows up
to 1 million tokens and they're going to
need them just to be able to name off
what their model is called. But if these
Quinn models are models that are
normally in your large language arsenal,
well, they have a much longer context
window. Now, this is starting to become
much more normal where these models have
these huge context windows. And I think
pretty soon we're going to get to a
point where context windows aren't even
important because they're all just going
to be so big that it doesn't matter how
much text you feed into a model when
you're chatting with it. And while we're
on the topic of large language model
news after the big GPT5 launch and a ton
of fallout around the fact that they
took away the 40 model, ChatGpt put 40
back into chat GPT. So, if that was your
favorite model and you like it better
than GPT5, you can go back and use 40
again. I did a whole video breaking down
the drama and the fallout of GPT5. So,
make sure you check that video out if
you want to learn about all of the stuff
that people hate about chat GPT5. And in
response to GPT5 coming out this week,
XAI made Gro 4 free for everybody
worldwide. Previous to this, Grock 4 was
only available on one of their paid
plans, and you can use the older Grock
models for free, but now Gro 4 is
available to everybody, which honestly
feels like a move that was a response to
GPT5 being available in the free
version. Also, in some anthropic Claude
news, Sonnet 4 now also supports a
million tokens of context, but I believe
it's only in the API, and I believe it's
only on Sonnet. So, their new Claude
Opus 4.1, which I found to be the best
available coding model out there, I
don't think has the million token
context window yet. It says Claude
Sonnet 4 now supports up to 1 million
tokens of context in the anthropic API.
So, even if you go to claude.ai, their
chatbot that's available on their
website, it doesn't sound like you're
going to get a million token context to
be able to just dump almost unlimited
information into it. It's only through
the API. So, if you're using an app like
a cursor or a wind surf or you're
building your own product that uses
claude under the hood, you get access to
this million token context window. And
for those that are interested, the
pricing does go up when you need more
than 200,000 tokens of context window.
So, just something to keep in mind if
you are developing on top of this. Last
week, we saw Genie 3, which allowed you
to give it an image or a video and then
you can actually enter that world and
like navigate the world with your arrow
keys. and it looked really, really cool,
but we didn't get access to it yet.
Well, this week, this Skywork AI
released Matrix Game 2.0, which seems to
be the opensource version of what Genie
showed off last week, and it's available
right now. If we take a peek at their
demo page here, we can check out a few
of the types of scenes that it
generated. Now, it's not in the highest
quality, but you can see they have this
world that they can move around, and I
believe it just started from a single
input image. Here's another example
where they're just moving around in this
world using the WD keys. They're able to
do it across GTA scenes. Long video
generation. Let's see what these look
like. This one's a 59 second video
generation here where they're just
moving around this park scene. And this
is all openly available. My buddy Balavo
here, I feel like he explains what's
going on pretty decently. Matrix 3D does
a smart thing. It generates a full 360
panorama first, then extends temporarily
with camera control, then lifts it to
3D. So, you give it an image like this,
and then it uses a model to figure out
and sort of guess what the rest of that
image would look like in 360. And then
that helps create the consistency so
that when you do look around, it stays
consistent every time you look around.
The full scene in 360 is always going to
look the same. Older versions of this
type of technology, you would look in
one direction, you'd turn around, and
then if you looked back in the original
direction, it would be a different scene
than original. Now, it stays consistent.
And a lot of that is because it seems to
like outpaint a panoramic version.
That's my understanding. I could be
stating some of this wrong, but it's
really, really interesting. And this
would be something I would demo on this
video, but I'm not because it requires a
lot of compute power right now. So the
model and the model weights are
available on Hugging Face and over on
GitHub here. So you can actually
download this and run them locally on
your computer. However, if we look at
the requirements, it requires an Nvidia
GPU with at least 24 GB of memory. I'm
currently on a Mac that has 512 GB of
memory, but it doesn't have an Nvidia
GPU in it. They also tested it on Linux
with 64 GB of RAM. So, it requires a
little bit more than what most consumers
are going to have in a computer right
now and therefore I didn't really feel
like it was worth trying to demo on a
separate PC because most people aren't
going to have the required compute to do
it. Hopefully, we get some cloud
versions and people set this up on
various like GPU clouds like hugging
face or whatever so that we can test it,
but I haven't come across any that work
yet. If you're a fan of MidJourney, it
got a little bit of an update this week.
We previously talked about how you can
do HD videos with MidJourney, but only
on the higher tier plans. Well, now you
can actually do HD video generation on
standard subscriptions. So, the
lower-end plans, you can now generate
the HD videos. You can do smaller batch
video jobs. now only one or two videos
at a time. They separated out mood
boards onto its own page. And they've
changed the thumbnails on video jobs and
improved the video moderation a little
bit. So, some quality of life updates,
plus more people having access to this
HD video generation feature. The company
Pika Labs teased a new update this week
called their audiodriven performance
model that actually does pretty decent
lip-syncing, and it can do it in 6
seconds or less in HD, which is wild. It
says rolling out soon in the Pika Social
app. I checked before recording. It
wasn't in my app yet, so can't demo it
yet, but we can look a little bit at
their video here.
So, I went on this date the other night
and I knew it was doomed the moment he
said, "I don't really believe in sauce."
Y'all better be on his app for like 15
hours a day.
I'm the kind of girl your playlist
writes breakup songs about.
But pretty impressive for the speed. 6
seconds for HD video and the lip sync is
I mean as good as pretty much any of the
AI lips sync we've seen. So excited to
get my hands on that. Not out quite yet.
If you remember last week I showed off a
feature from VO3 that allows you to draw
on your images and it will actually
follow what you drew on the images in
the output video. Well, Higsfield rolled
that out as a feature. They added this
feature called draw to video where you
give it an image. You could kind of
sketch on the image, tell it what you
want it to do, and it will follow
whatever prompts you put on the image.
So, the same thing we saw that you were
able to do with V3 is now a feature of
Higsfield AI. We also talked last week
about this Kaggle from Google, basically
testing AI models against each other at
various games, and the first competition
was chess. Well, at the time of
recording that video, Grock 4 was
actually in the lead, but by the time
the entire tournament was done,
ChatGpt's 03 model actually won. Now,
GBT5 wasn't in the mix, but you could
actually see the entire tournament
bracket here. 04 Mini crushed Deep Seek
R1 4 to nothing. 03 crushed Chem K2 4 to
nothing. Gemini 2.5 4 to nothing against
Claude Opus 4, which surprising to me.
And then Gro 4 beat Gemini 2.5 Flash 4
to nothing. Being a Flash model versus
Gro 4. This one is not surprising at
all. But then we saw that 03 beat 04
Mini. Gro 4 beat Gemini 2.5 Pro. And
then the finals came down to 03 versus
Grock 4 and 03 swept Gro. So I thought
that was a fun little tournament. I'd
love to see more games like this to see
which AIs beat out other games. I just
think it's kind of fun to watch. One of
the godfathers of AI, Jeffrey Hinton,
was on CNN this week to share some of
his fears about AI as well as how he
thinks we need to proceed with AI to
sort of mitigate some of the potential
disasters from it. So these are some of
the important clips. Do you still
believe that 10 to 20% chance of AIs
wiping out humans is possible?
Oh yes. If we can't figure out a
solution to how we can still be around
when they're much smarter than us and
much more powerful than us will be
toast.
He also talked about how these models
will eventually be smarter than us and
how we need to like train maternal
instincts into the models. Most of the
AI experts believe that sometime in the
next 5 to 20 years we'll make AIs that
are smarter than people and they'll
probably end up much smarter than
people. And there's very few examples we
know of smarter things being controlled
by less smart things. In fact, pretty
much the only example we know is a
mother being controlled by her baby. To
make that happen, evolution built
maternal instincts into the mother. And
if we don't do something like that with
these alien beings that we're creating,
we're going to be history. And what he's
basically referring to there is what
people in the AI world call the
alignment problem where they're worried
that as AI gets smarter and smarter, it
may fall out of alignment with what
humans goals are. It may figure out that
if it needs to stop climate change, it
needs to rid the world of people to
solve that problem. Right? But we need
to make sure that as AIs get smarter and
smarter that it is aligned with human
values. So Jeffrey Hinton is suggesting
that we make these AIs love humans, have
that maternal instinct, want to protect
humans, and really train that into the
models. So no matter what else they do,
they have this overarching sort of
philosophy that they are here to serve
and help humans and not the other way
around. But hearing someone like Jeffrey
Hinton, who basically invented the
technology we're playing with today and
then stopped working on it to sort of
warn the world of its dangers, it's it's
kind of scary. But I don't want to end
on that note. So, I want to show a cool
robot and something that I am actually
excited about. And that's that this
week, Figure Robotics unveiled a robot
that can actually fold your laundry for
you. Which is funny cuz last week I
showed off a robot that was like pulling
laundry out of a washing machine and
putting it into a washing machine. And I
was like, "Show me a robot that can fold
my laundry once it's done and I'll be
excited about it." Well, that was figure
also. So, the figure robot is able to
actually put clothes in and out of a
machine and even fold your laundry. So,
that's something to look forward to.
Let's hope it doesn't try to destroy us
all at some point.
We're going to die. It's every man for
himself. Help me, Leela. But that's what
I got for you this week. A lot of news
that flew under the radar with all the
chat GPT and Gemini and Elon Musk and
Claude craziness that happened over the
last couple of weeks. And uh still some
pretty fun exciting stuff and some new
toys that we get to work with and play
with. A few that I thought we'd be able
to play with but apparently still aren't
rolled out. But all in all, progress is
happening and I'm here to keep up with
it and to try to help you keep up with
it. So, if you're interested in keeping
up with all the latest AI news and
getting all the latest AI tutorials,
make sure you like this video and
subscribe to this channel. I will make
sure more stuff like this shows up in
your YouTube feed. And thank you so much
for hanging out with me and nerding out
with me on these videos. It is so much
fun to just find all the latest news and
toys and go and play with them and show
people what they're capable of and what
we're getting ourselves into in this AI
world. So, once again, thanks. Really
appreciate you. Hopefully, I'll see you
in the next one. Bye-bye. Thank you so
much for nerding out with me today. If
you like videos like this, make sure to
give it a thumbs up and subscribe to
this channel. I'll make sure more videos
like this show up in your YouTube feed.
And if you haven't already, check out
futuretools.io where I share all the
coolest AI tools and all the latest AI
news. And there's an awesome free
newsletter. Thanks again. Really
appreciate you. See you in the next one.